Guide to the Allen Ginsberg film and video archive, 1983 - 1996
Department of Special Collections
- Ginsberg, Family and Friends: Photos 40-54. (Box 14, Folder 135)
  Time in: 4:00:31 Time out: 4:19:24 Total Time: 18m 55s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are many photos of college age Allen alone, and with Cassady, Kerouac, Burroughs and Corso.
- Ginsberg, Family and Friends: Photos 55-62. (Box 14, Folder 136)
  Time in: 5:00:22 Time out: 5:09:31 Total Time: 9m 9s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are college age photos of Ginsberg, Corso, Burroughs, Orlovsky, Kerouac and Cassady.
- Ginsberg, Family and Friends: Photos 63-81. (Box 14, Folder 137)
  Time in: 6:00:30 Time out: 6:31:23 Total Time: 29m 3s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are single photos of young Huncke and Orlovsky as well as a photo of a very young Dylan with John Hammond and a slightly older Dylan with Ginsberg. Also photos of Ginsberg as the King of May in Prague in 1965 and with Havel in Prague in 1992.
- Ginsberg, Family and Friends: Photos 82-97. (Box 14, Folder 138)
  Time in: 7:00:31 Time out: 7:31:44 Total Time: 30m 48s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are individual and group photos of Edith Ginsberg, Louis Ginsberg, Allen Ginsberg, Corso, Burroughs, Orlovsky, Huncke. Also 9 Kerouac photos by Ginsberg.
- Ginsberg, Family and Friends: Photos 98-121. (Box 14, Folder 139)
  Time in: 8:00:30 Time out: 8:29:50 Total Time: 29m 20s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are 12 individual young Cassady photos, most taken by Ginsberg and 8 photos of Burroughs at different ages, all taken by Ginsberg.
- Ginsberg, Family and Friends: Photos 122-134. (Box 14, Folder 140)
  Time in: 9:00:30 Time out: 9:30:22 Total Time: 29m 49s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are a number of photos of Burroughs at various stages in his life as well as many photos of a young Ginsberg and a young Corso (taken by Allen). There are also a variety of shots of the painting of Peter Orlovsky by Robert LaVigne.
- Ginsberg, Family and Friends: Photos 134-143. (Box 15, Folder 141)
  Time in: 10:00:31 Time out: 10:29:57 Total Time: 31m 51s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are numerous shots of young Orlovsky and Ginsberg. There are also shots of older Orlovsky by Ginsberg and Aronson. There are also photos of the First Blues album cover.
- Ginsberg Family Photos: Additional Photos. (Box 15, Folder 142)
  Time in: 12:00:31 Time out: 12:31:22 Total Time: 31m 4s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are two photos of Naomi in her younger years and one formal portrait of Louis Ginsberg as a young man and a number of photos of Allen around college age.
- Ginsberg Family Photos: Additional Photos. (Box 15, Folder 143)
  Time in: 13:00:31 Time out: 13:29:43 Total Time: 29m 12s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  There are a variety of photos of Louis Ginsberg, Huncke, Burroughs, Kerouac, Orlovsky and a group shot of the poets from the Gallery Six reading taken outside of City Lights Books and a photo of Ginsberg as the King of May, Prague, 1965.
- Book Covers and Additional Ginsberg Family Photos. (Box 15, Folder 144)
  Time in: 1:00:30 Time out: 1:19:46 Total Time: 19m 14 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  Shots of Kerouac's book covers, photos of Edith and Louis, young Allen in mirror.
  - Kerouac Book Covers. (Box 15, Folder 144)
    Time in: 1:00:30 Time out: 1:12:38 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Various shots of the following book covers: On The Road, Dr. Sax, The Subterranean, Mexico City Blues, Visions of Cody.
  - Edith and Louis Ginsberg Photos. (Box 15, Folder 144)
    Time in: 1:12:39 Time out: 1:18:44 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Various permutations of 3 photos of Edith and Louis in Europe just after their marriage.
  - Young Allen Ginsberg. (Box 15, Folder 144)
    Time in: 1:18:45 Time out: 1:19:46 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    An interesting photo of a 25 year old Ginsberg looking at himself in a mirror.
- Jack Kerouac's 1969 New York Times Obituary. (Box 15, Folder 145)
  Time in: 14:00:30 Time out: 14:12:55 Total Time: 12m 25s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  Kerouac's New York Times printed obituary (re-do's -- various camera animations).
- Ginsberg flipping through book: Allen Ginsberg Photographs. (Box 15, Folder 146)
  Time in: 11:00:20 Time out: 11:21:50 Total Time: 21m 34s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  Various photos from Ginsberg's Allen Ginsberg Photographs, and Ginsberg flipping through its pages, commenting.
- Stan Brakhage and Allen Ginsberg. (Box 15, Folder 147)
  Time in: 1:01:00 Time out: 1:03:38 Total Time: 2m 38s Source: Mini DV Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  At Ginsberg's apartment, Boulder, CO, July 11, 1996. Brakhage paints an abstract portrait of Ginsberg on 16mm film while waiting for Ginsberg to awaken from a nap.
  - Brakhage explaining his film style. (Folder 147)
    Time in: 1:01:17 Time out: 1:02:04 Source: Mini DV Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Brakhage describes how his feelings for Ginsberg translate into "plein air" (open-air) abstractions on film.
  - Stan Brakhage interview. (Folder 147)
    Time in: 1:02:22 Time out: 1:02:35 Source: Mini DV Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Brakhage comments on being friends with Ginsberg off and on for over 30 years.
  - Ginsberg and Brakhage together. (Folder 147)
    Time in: 1:02:43 Time out: 1:03:38 Source: Mini DV Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Ginsberg views the finished 16mm film portrait as Brakhage tells him that in order to see it, he should blink his eyes at 24 frames per second. Ginsberg begins blinking. Brakhage laughs.
- Philip Glass Interview, Part I. (Box 15, Folder 148)
  Time in: 1:02:17 Time out: 1:30:15 Total Time: 27m 58s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  Naropa Institute, Boulder, CO, July 17, 1999. Philip Glass talks about his collaborative efforts and long time friendship with Allen Ginsberg, as well as Ginsberg's death.
  - Philip Glass on meeting Allen Ginsberg. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:02:17 Time out: 1:04:11 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    When Glass arrived in New York City, he observed Ginsberg reading poetry and gradually got to know him.
  - Philip Glass on his first collaboration with Ginsberg. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:04:13 Time out: 1:05:45 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    In 1987, they first collaborated on "Hydrogen Jukebox".
  - Philip Glass on meeting Geleg Rinpoche. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:05:46 Time out: 1:07:15 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    In 1988, Geleg became the Buddhist teacher for both Ginsberg and Glass.
  - Philip Glass on Ginsberg's spiritual attraction to Geleg. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:07:20 Time out: 1:09:50 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Geleg Rinpoche replaces Trungpa Rinpoche as Ginsberg's Buddhist teacher.
  - Philip Glass on Ginsberg's stroke. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:09:56 Time out: 1:14:19 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Geleg came to New York when Ginsberg had a stroke to help prepare him for death.
  - Philip Glass on Ginsberg's death. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:15:54 Time out: 1:17:01 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    People from all the different areas of Ginsberg's life were present in his loft when he died.
  - Philip Glass on Ginsberg's death. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:17:24 Time out: 1:17:34 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Ginsberg shared both his life and his death with everyone.
  - Philip Glass on poetry and music. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:17:48 Time out: 1:20:31 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Glass discusses his improvisations with Patti Smith.
  - Philip Glass on his involvement in the early New York scene. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:20:51 Time out: 1:25:03 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    In 1959, much of the poetry, music and art were centered around Yoko Ono and Ginsberg.
  - Philip Glass on his early influences. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:25:13 Time out: 1:26:42 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Glass was influenced by Ginsberg, John Cage, Ravi Shankar, and the Living Theater.
  - Philip Glass on the way Ginsberg led his life. (Folder 148)
    Time in: 1:27:01 Time out: 1:29:51 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Ginsberg always said that there is nothing to hide and lived by those words.
- Philip Glass Interview, Part II. (Box 15, Folder 149)
  Time in: 2:00:16 Time out: 2:07:14 Total Time: 6m 58s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  - Philip Glass on Allen Ginsberg's teaching style. (Folder 149)
    Time in: 2:00:16 Time out: 2:02:25 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Ginsberg's teaching style allowed for each individual's uniqueness to be expressed through poetry.
  - Philip Glass comments on Ginsberg's death. (Folder 149)
    Time in: 2:03:25 Time out: 2:06:07 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    We internalize people who we are close to, therefore they never really die.
- Patti Smith Interview. (Box 15, Folder 150)
  Time in: 0:00:00 Time out: 0:32:33 Total Time: 32m 33s Source: DVCAM Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: 3/4" Window Dub
  Interview with Patti Smith at Electric Lady Land recording studio in New York City, February 15, 2001
  - Patti Smith on first meeting Allen Ginsberg. (Folder 150)
    Time in: 0:00:35 Time out: 0:06:55 Source: DVCAM Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: 3/4" Window Dub
    Patti Smith tells a humorous story about her first meeting with Allen and a fun misunderstanding.
  - Patti Smith describing Allen' s ability to comfort her. (Folder 150)
    Time in: 0:06:55 Time out: 0:12:50 Source: DVCAM Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: 3/4" Window Dub
    Patti describes Allen's ability to bring her out of a ten year retirement in 1995 and help her resume her music career.
  - Story about Allen introducing Patti at a benefit concert. (Folder 150)
    Time in: 0:13:40 Time out: 0:15:21 Source: DVCAM Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: 3/4" Window Dub
    Patti laughingly remembers an incredibly long and embarrassing introduction that finally made her want to meet the person Allen was introducing, until she realized that person was her.
  - Patti at Allen's death bed. (Folder 150)
    Time in: 0:20:20 Time out: 0:25:40 Source: DVCAM Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: 3/4" Window Dub
    Patti describes the amazing variety of people from all of Allen's worlds that were at his side at the time of his death.
  - Patti discussing Gregory Corso's reaction to Allen's death. (Folder 150)
    Time in: 0:25:45 Time out: 0:28:05 Source: DVCAM Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: 3/4" Window Dub
    Patti becomes aware that by witnessing Allen's passing, Corso learned how to die in a graceful manner. At one point, he says, "Allen, oh my Allen."
  - Patti talks about her philosophy on death. (Folder 150)
    Time in: 0:28:05 Time out: 0:32:33 Source: DVCAM Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: 3/4" Window Dub
    Patti believes that Allen is still around in spirit when she performs his work. She gives a concrete example involving her tooth.
- "Ballad of the Skeletons". (Box 16, Folder 151)
  Time in: 1:00:00 Time out: 1:13:32 Total Time: 13m 32s Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  Mercury Records publicity video featuring "Ballad of the Skeletons" and additional interview and video material, including Ginsberg and film director Gus Van Sant. Release date: October 8, 1996.
  - Allen Ginsberg and Gus Van Sant. (Folder 151)
    Time in: 1:01:11 Time out: 1:02:24 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Allen talks about the creation of the music for the music video.
  - Allen Ginsberg and Gus Van Sant. (Folder 151)
    Time in: 1:03:30 Time out: 1:04:27 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Gus talks about his style of layering and montage.
  - "Ballad of the Skeletons". (Folder 151)
    Time in: 1:04:27 Time out: 1:08:36 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    The full music video (uncensored, non-MTV version).
  - Additional Footage. (Folder 151)
    Time in: 1:08:40 Time out: 1:10:42 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Includes outtakes and behind the scene footage from the making of the video.
  - Additional Footage. (Folder 151)
    Time in: 1:10:45 Time out: 1:13:32 Source: Beta Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
    Additional footage of Ginsberg and Van Sant discussing their feelings about the younger generation's attitudes toward protest and environmental issues.
- Firing Line: William F. Buckley and Allen Ginsberg. (Box 16, Folder 152)
  Time in: 0:00:00 Time out: 0:53:50 Total Time: 53m 50s Source: 3/4" Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  Episode #99 from 1968. An amazing and entertaining exchange between a conservative Buckley and a very liberal Ginsberg. Great television!
- Firing Line: William F. Buckley, Jack Kerouac and Ed Sanders. (Box 16, Folder 153)
  Time in: 0:00:00 Time out: 0:52:25 Total Time: 52m 25s Source: 3/4" Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  Episode #113. Kerouac's 1969 appearance, just before his death. He is very anti-hippie and quite drunk.
- The Life and Times of Allen Ginsberg (Box 16, Folder 154)
  Time in: 1:00:00 Time out: 2:22:20 Total Time: 82m 20s Source: D2 Master Screening Format: 3/4" Window Dub Dubbing format: Beta Dub Master
  The award winning documentary film made by Jerry Aronson with Ginsberg's full cooperation. Completed in the Fall of 1992.